Donna Tjandra – Curriculum Vitae

dotjand@umich.edu
https://detjandra.github.io/

INTRODUCTION & INTERESTS

I am a PhD student studying computer science at the University of Michigan, and I am advised by Professor Jenna Wiens. My research lies at the intersection of machine learning and healthcare. Broadly, my interests cover topics like survival analysis and noisy label learning in the context of real-world problems such as predicting the onset of Alzheimer's disease and sepsis.

EDUCATION

2018-present

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

In progress: Doctor of Philosophy

- Advisor: Professor Jenna Wiens
- Dissertation topic: Learning from clinical data in the presence of noise and uncertainty
- GPA: 3.93/4.00

2020: Master's of Science in Computer Science

2013-2018

University of Toronto, St. George

Bachelor's of Science

- Molecular Genetics and Computer Science
- GPA: 3.87/4.00

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2018-present	University of Michigan, Graduate Student Research Assistant
	 Advisor: Professor Jenna Wiens
	 Topic: Developing novel machine learning techniques for survival
	analysis and noisy labels with Alzheimer's disease and sepsis
2017-2018	University of Toronto, Undergraduate Researcher
	 Advisor: Professor Kenneth Jackson
	 Topic: Synthesizing training data for deep convolutional neural
	networks to detect lung nodules on frontal chest radiographs
2015-2017	University of Toronto, Undergraduate Researcher
	 Advisor: Professor Charles Boone & Natasha Pascoe
	 Topic: Discovering novel inhibitors for deubiquitinating enzymes
	using yeast two-hybrid

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. **Tjandra D**, He Y, Wiens J. A Hierarchical Approach to Multi-Event Survival Analysis. In *Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence 2021 May 18* (Vol. 35, No. 1, pp. 591-599)
- 2. **Tjandra D**, Migrino RQ, Giordani B, Wiens J. Cohort discovery and risk stratification for Alzheimer's disease: an electronic health record-based approach. *Alzheimer's &*

Dementia: Translational Research & Clinical Interventions, 6(1), e12035. 2020

- 3. Belth C, Kamran F, **Tjandra D**, Koutra D. When to remember where you came from: Node representation learning in higher-order networks. *IEEE/ACM International Conference on Advances in Social Networks Analysis and Mining (ASONAM)*. 2019.
- 4. Pascoe N, Seetharaman A, Teyra J, Manczyk N, Satori AM, **Tjandra D**, Makhnevych T, Schwerdtfeger C, Brasher BB, Moffat J, Costanzo M, Boone C, Sicheri F, Sidhu SS. Yeast Two-Hybrid Analysis for Ubiquitin-variant Inhibitors of Human Deubiquitinases. *Journal of Molecular Biology.* 436(6): 1160-1171. 2019
- 5. Goyal D, **Tjandra D**, Migrino RQ, Giordani B, Syed Z, Wiens J. Characterizing heterogeneity in the progression of Alzheimer's disease using longitudinal clinical and neuroimaging biomarkers. *Alzheimer's & Dementia: Diagnosis, Assessment & Disease Monitoring.* 10: 629-637. 2018

POSTER PRESENTATIONS

- 1. **Tjandra D**, Migrino RQ, Giordani B, Wiens J. An EHR-Based Risk Stratification Tool for Probable AD. *Alzheimers Association International Conference*. 2019
- 2. **Tjandra D**, Migrino RQ, Giordani B, Wiens J. An EHR-Based Cohort Discovery Tool for Identifying Probable AD. *Alzheimers Association International Conference*. 2019
- 3. **Tjandra D** & Cao W, Barfett J, Jackson K. Synthesizing Training Data for a Deep Convolutional Network to Detect Abnormalities in Frontal Chest Radiographs. *University of Toronto Undergraduate Poster Fair in Computer Science*. 2017
- 4. **Tjandra D** & Tung E, Pascoe N, Costanzo M, Sidhu SS, Boone CM. Discovering Novel Ubiquitin Variant Inhibitors of Deubiquitinases in vivo: Strategies using Budding Yeast. *University of Toronto Undergraduate Poster Fair in Molecular Genetics*. 2016
- 5. **Tjandra D**, Pascoe N, Costanzo M, Sidhu SS, Boone CM. Discovering Novel Ubiquitin Variant Inhibitors of Deubiquitinases in vivo: Strategies using Budding Yeast. *University of Toronto Undergraduate Poster Fair in Molecular Genetics*. 2015

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2021

University of Michigan

• Graduate student instructor for <u>Discrete Math</u> (EECS 203)

2017-2018

University of Toronto

• Teaching Assistant for <u>Introduction to the Theory of Computer Science</u> (CSC 236)

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES & OUTREACH

2021

University of Michigan, F.E.M.M.E.S.

• Assisted in facilitating F.E.M.M.E.S. (females excelling more in match engineering and the sciences) explore

2020-present	University of Michigan CSE DEI focus group
	 An organization of students and faculty to promote DEI (diversity,
	equity and inclusion) in the CSE (computer science and
	engineering) department, serving as a member
2020-present	University of Michigan, Onboarding Buddy
	 Serving as point of contact for new graduate students
2020	University of Michigan, SURE
	 Mentored an undergraduate student in research for the SURE
	(Summer Undergraduate Research Experience) program, resulting in a co-authored publication ¹ at AAAI
2019-present	University of Michigan, CSEG Wellness
	 A group from CSEG (Computer Science and Engineering Graduate
	student organization) at the University of Michigan to promote
	overall wellness and mental health, serving as a member
2019	University of Michigan, Explore Graduate Studies
	 A program to promote participation of underrepresented minorities
	in graduate studies in computer science, served as a volunteer
2018-2019	Michigan AI Symposium
	 An event bringing together AI (artificial intelligence) researchers
	and practitioners from Southeastern Michigan to discuss the latest
	advancements in AI, served as a volunteer
2016-2018	University of Toronto, Undergraduate Theory Group
	 Served as a member
2014	University of Toronto, Student panel for math course selection
	 Served as a panellist

HONORS & AWARDS

2017	First Prize at the Undergraduate Summer Research Poster Fair
	(Department of Computer Science, University of Toronto)
2015 & 2016	Undergraduate Student Research Award (USRA)
	from the Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council (NSERC)
2014 & 2015	Chancellor's Scholarship funded by the St. Hilda's Board
2013-2017	Dean's Honor List (University of Toronto)

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Computational	Knowledgeable of: Python, Java, Verilog, C, Matlab, SQL
	Also knowledgeable with training deep neural networks using Pytorch
Biological	Wet lab skills such as DNA extraction and protein purification